[Music]
hello and thank you for watching
accordingly to the Shopify website
millions of entrepreneurs choose Shopify
platform to run their business from
first sales to Global Brands and if
these entrepreneurs do the things right
and get it and their sales increase soon
they notice they need something else in
addition to Shopify to run processes
outside of the e-commerce think about
Finance or tax or procurement and you
already know which system best to
address these requirements it's actually
not a joke accordingly to evidences we
receive from partner who took this
opportunity very seriously and reach out
to multiple Merchant the sales cycle is
about 2 weeks in average but it can be
as short as 8 days that sounds
impressive that's why our job from as
Microsoft is to make sure that this
connector actually connects these two
apps seamlessly as possible and we are
again focusing on the making connector
better investing into product
information management on one side and
Order handling on another side which is
in reality 80% of connector let's see
what we added or improved in this
release every business is unique and and
uh software which automate business must
support this uniqueness and flexible
business processes and not to restrict
business Central doing great job in this
area as well as Shopify does and it has
multiple capabilities and today we are
looking at one which is called custom
Fields you as a
merchant can Define custom fields or
custom data and attach them to uh most
important entities like products or
variants and these fields can have a
different data types and let's see how
they will be rendered in the product
list I will close the administration
part and navigate to product and open
the one of the products our famous
London wheel chair and scroll down and
what you can see that system Shopify
automatically added predefined meta
fields or custom fields in the in the
page so now I'm as a Shopify admin can
modify these values and specify some
data but can we get them into the
business Central thank you Andre yes of
course we can if you go to your products
and then synchronize products from
Shopify the product that you was just
looking at is imported and there's a new
action here called meta Fields uh you
can see all the meta fields that you saw
in Shopify admin is also uh import into
business Central um connector right now
uh only Imports them but uh we left it
to you to write uh your custom
extensions to actually do mappings with
them uh I already did something uh
wanted to take a close look to
substitute so I have the uh the code for
the extension here which goes through
the meta Fields uh for this product and
then finds the substitute one and for
the substitute uh value of that meta
field it creates a item substitution
let's see if that
worked open the London
chair and then I'll just search for
substitutions as you can see the Mexico
chair was added as a substitution uh for
this London chair based on the meta
field uh that we synced from
Shopify with this release uh in addition
to meta Fields uh you can also
synchronize uh translations in order to
grow uh in different markets uh very
rapidly uh there's a new action again uh
in your Shopify Shop Card called
languages you can import the languages
from Shopify and U Mark the ones that
you want to sync translations with uh
for this uh we selected uh French as a
language and then we want to sync
translations with it so let's see uh
what happens if I add an item uh from
business Central to Shopify how will
that look I'll go to products again and
add
items and then I
select this item that I have already
translations for and then hit Okay so
this item now will be added as a product
to Shopify and then let's see if there
are translations for it all right I can
see that product was imported with
extended text attributes and
descriptions or everything is in English
because our default language is English
Let's uh explore how I can see different
languages I can navigate to more actions
and check localized app which will show
me different translations but let's uh
navigate to the preview mode and see how
buyer will see our product in the
internet so we can see that default
language is English but I can because I
configured my store to support two
languages display information in French
let me pick it and we do not want to
translate it back to English okay that's
what we see French typ
French extended textt and also
attributes and even attributes values
are
translated let's navigate back to the
product
list business Central supports items and
item variants as well as Shopify which
also support products but also support
multiple options which can be combined
into variant so different systems
different apps have different purpose
that's why it might be different how you
decide to configure your product list in
one product or in another for example
you can use variants in the Shopify site
but import it into business Central as a
flight list and you can do that today
with a SKU mapping field which can help
you to do that but what if you want to
push data from business Central to
Shopify and add
extra item which is registered in
business Central as item for multiple
reasons maybe it's needed of material
associated with it or something else and
you want to add this uh item as variant
in the product can we do that yeah of
course we can uh we introduced a new
action called add items as Shopify
variants uh in the Shopify product list
uh if I select the London chair and then
use this action and then if I wanted to
add the Blue version of it as a a
variant and hit
okay now this variant uh is this item is
as as a variant to this Shopify product
uh let's see how that looks in
Shopify yes it worked now in the London
Fiel chair I can see two variants let's
open the list and scroll down Yes red
and 1908 yeah you still need to do some
work for example navigate here and
change the title to whatever you like
for example blue we don't have the full
control on titles yet in the Shopify
apis we working on this uh but with this
Easy Action just one click you got
variant created which is linked to
business Central product it means
availability levels and prices are
synchronized okay about prices so price
is coming from business Central to
Shopify and you can configure default
prices which will be inserted to the
Shopify uh
product in the business Central Shopify
shop card and these prices can use
customer price group customer discount
group and combination of those in
previous release when we added support
for Shopify B2B we also support now
catalogs which can be uh which can be
linked to the company in the Shopify and
on business Central s you can also
assign customer price group and customer
discount group to this catalog to make
sure that group of companies to whom
this catalog is allocated see the
special prices in the in the store when
they do shopping but in business Central
we have more advanced capabilities I as
a user in business Central can decide
that this specific customer will get an
extra discount or special price just
because yeah how can we achieve the same
uh functionality with Shopify
connector I'll show you how if you go to
uh related in your shop cut and select
catalogs uh you'll notice a new field
which I uh exposed by personalization uh
is set visible false but you can always
make it visible by
personalization uh it is customer number
so what I will do is uh for this catalog
named trade research I'm just going to
use trade research as the customer and
then I will sync prices for these two
cataloges and then see how the prices
are
syncing prices are synced how does it
look in Shopify yeah it's not very not
just ible in business Central but let's
take a look in details what we can see
here as I mentioned before so the
product main product got price
accordingly to the settings in the
Shopify shop cart on business Central
and it is like
195 but we also have two catalogs we can
have a generic B2B catalog which you saw
is already allocated to two different
companies so we can see two different
companies a datum and TR
research all right and also on top Tre
research has an extra catalog special
one uh allocated to it all right and it
has a special price now if I will go
here and scroll down I can see that
price is
155 let's try to do it in practice and
see how prices will be respected by
Shopify I will navigate to orders and
start by creating a new order I will
select the product
Paris
chair all right now it's Danish crowns
but let's switch different Market we
switch to us it will also update prices
to US Dollars again 195 you remember we
saw it in the product card all right now
let's add customer and we will start by
adding Robert who is actually uh buyer
for aatam Corporation we selected aatam
Corporation and prices has changed so
now it is
180 but now let's remove
customer and switch somebody else it
will be Helen and Helen works as a buyer
in TR
research and as we remember the Tre
research company has two catalogs
Associated B2B and special one where it
has lower price for this specific
product interesting story about this
specific feature this feature is added
via code development project you can see
another video explaining the
fundamentals of this
one story is we know that this
requirement is uh rather important
because we heard it from several
Merchants already and we plan to add it
but it was not clear about the timelines
and then one Merchant is actually
proactively suggested that they would
like to contribute so Merchant and the
partner who was helping them with
implementation they submitted this code
to the GitHub where we have our
extension code is available so we kind
of created a v team and uh together with
Merchant partner and Microsoft make sure
that this functionality is now available
in the standard product and this is
win-win situation because now Merchant
and uh partner don't need to support
this code because as soon as development
is done and hand over to Microsoft now
Microsoft is responsible for M for
maintenance and support of this
functionality and it also win for
Microsoft because Now functionality is
available for other customers using the
same connector everybody
wins what else has changed in the
connector something which is not really
visible to you but important and to
explain I will start by telling how
Shopify works and especially from
development perspective because Shopify
often releasing new functionality and it
also updates apis every quarter and we
at Microsoft soft rely on these apis so
every quarter there is a new version and
it version will stay current for one
year to make sure that we aligned with
Shopify release Cycles H Microsoft
uptake the latest available version of
API with every major release to reduce
possible breaking changes or behavior
changes in the minor updates so it means
in the wave 1 which is usually April we
use uh API released in January by
Shopify and for October we will be using
a version of API which become available
in July all right what does it give us
uh something not very visible right now
but we are now prepared for the big
change which Shopify already announced
and started u slowly rolling out already
it's the are lifting restrictions on
number of variants you can have so now
you can have up to 2,000 of variant
under one product and our connector
already works with it you can test it if
you have a development store which uses
the latest Shopify version but what else
we we have in the connector yeah um as
Andre said uh we're always making sure
that we use the latest and greatest
Shopify API version and you'll notice
that your API version in your shop cut
is changed to 2024 July and is supported
for a year uh with this version Shopify
requires us to send uh weight unit when
we send the weight of a variant of a or
a product uh for that we introduce a new
uh setting here it's called weight unit
under item synchronization Tab and we
automatically synchronize this from
Shopify but you can always change this
in business
Central and also uh under uh return and
refund processing you can see that uh
there's a new field called return
location priority and it has two options
the default return location is like how
it used to work before it refers to this
uh return location so you can check uh
select the
location and the next one is the
original default location this is new uh
what will this will do this will
actually try to uh pick the locate R
return location uh for theop from the
Shopify refr and if it cannot find it
for a reason uh like uh if the item is
restocked in multiple locations it will
go back to the default return
location you can also do a lot more with
shipping charges in this release uh if
you go to your shipment method
mapping now uh instead of just one uh
shipping charges type which is the GL
account you can do item or item charge I
already defined for the standard uh
shipping method here uh I want it to be
synced with uh a item charge and the
item charge is the Fright item so let's
see how that looks if I synchronize an
order
let's sing orders from
Shopify good a new order has come in I
can create a sales document for
it and I can use the link documents uh
fact box to uh go to that
order you can see uh in the sales lines
instead of the usual uh GL account for
the ship shipping charges now is using
the setting I've set is uh pointing to a
item charge the fright and it's already
assigned you can see that by uh drilling
down this qu to the assign field uh it's
distributed between uh two
items also if you look closely to
shipping and billing tab you'll notice
that the shipment method uh agent and
agent service is already set up from the
mapping that I just uh configured in my
shop cart with this release uh you can
also uh synchronize postal sales
invoices to Shopify uh let's also see
how that looks um all you need to do is
enable the setting from order
synchronization and processing tab you
just need to enable posted invoice
syn and to make sure that sync works
correctly you need to Define some
payment terms mapping I've already
selected the fixed as the primary one
this is the default one it will get the
uh the payment terms date from the uh
the invoice it
itself and all I need to do now is use
sync posted sales
invoices and I want to sync it for a
specific customer so I'm going to add
cell to customer number as a
filter and use
clao
loon now we synchronizing all the posted
sales invoices for this customer
customer good it's done let's see how
that looks in Shopify all right I can
see that our favorite customer loon
actually uh here and now we receive two
invoices or two orders and they look
slightly different uh on purpose because
we want to do demonstrate you a couple
of different scenarios first of all what
you can see it's paid or not paid yeah
and if it's we send this information if
it's completely paid in the business
Central then document also will be
marked as a paid in the Shopify we can
also open it and explore a little bit
what do we see here uh we can see that
most of items or basically everything is
created not as real item or variant but
as something which is called custom
product available on Shopify the reason
is because otherwise Shopify doesn't
allow us to provide specific tax
information and we think that right
totals will be very
important okay what you can see here as
well is the currency so here we can see
Canadian dollars yes so original
currency from the posted sales invoice
will be transferred here as well uh next
uh one this one has US dollar and its
pay pending payment you can see that is
due on September 30 Let's uh actually
collect payment and send invoice to the
customer review
it and send
now as a customer as Cloud I received
invoice but it also has a pay now button
so technically I can press it and enter
my credit card information to make sure
that this document is paid and payment
information will be in the Shopify so
now we kind of using Shopify now as a
payment integration technique I would
like to talk about payment processing a
little bit more so we're receiving
payment and sometimes usually when
company using uh gift cards or credit
limit uh there are more than one payment
uh transaction associated with order and
this created some difficulties in the
reconciliation at least this is what we
heard from the customers and in this
release we are adding a new extra
capability which should help you to more
easily reconcile payments with the
posted invoices and to demonstrate that
we and you can see them three different
invoices with a three different
scenarios uh one is like very basic one
it's a just amount and fully paid be by
credit card if you scroll to the next
one this one is a special one because it
has partial refund so like it was paid
but then some of this money will
returned to the customer and the last
one is actually the essential scenario
which we wanted to support is
when amount is splitted in two parts and
it's uh partially paid with a gift card
with $100 and the remaining part will be
paid by credit card let's see what we
can do in business Central to deal with
this uh payments and reconcile them to
invoices I have already imported those
orders and you can see uh they have an
invoice attached to them and the one
that Andre showed is partially refunded
uh so how can I actually Recon file them
all I need to do is go to cash receipt
journals and under uh prepare tab you'll
see a new action called suest Shopify
payments this will only show if you have
an active uh enabled
shop there you can actually choose uh a
Gateway and then the uh starting
document number and all that good stuff
uh you can see that this is under the
bad Shopify card so that's what I will
do I will use the bogus card Gateway as
so that I want to pull only transactions
from this Gateway into this uh
Journal so I have four Journal lines
created uh you can see uh there's one
for the normal order is the correct
amount and then this one right here is
1034 is the one that is refunded so if I
close this and then you'll see that this
amount is minus but this is positive and
it's pointing to a credit memo because
it's a refunded one and then this is the
one that has the um the gift card so it
only pulls the uh the amount that is not
paid by the gift card by the bogus so
you can post this and then reconcile uh
your Shopify transactions uh directly in
business Central um there's another way
to do this and let's uh show that uh for
gift card payments so you can go to
Shopify transaction
page you'll see that these are all the
transactions that we import when we
import ERS and you can see that there
were uh two gift cards one was
authorization one was the capture this
one was the actually one that took the
money from the gift card so you can
select this and again use suggest
Shopify payments and then use this batch
gift instead of the card and then put a
starting document number if you want to
uh you don't need to put a Gateway
because there's already uh a transaction
ID filter so you can just hit okay you
can see under dispatch Shopify gift the
gift card is ready to be reconciled for
$100 that's it that's how easy it is to
now reconcile Shopify payments in
business
Central impressive all right so where
you can get more details and read about
limitations or scenarios at of course
release plans there are several articles
searched by Shopify term because usually
they include Shopify in the title but
also you can find the documentation
documentation because we updated it
notice that majority of this changes are
coming from you because we are
addressing feedback uh received via
different channels either via support or
by ideas so if you have something we and
you think product is missing please
submit your
idea otherwise thank you for watching